seti.org 2010-12-31

# SETI Institute - SETI Institute Privacy Policy

**Here you'll find information about our commitment to ensuring the privacy of your personal information, such as your full name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or other identifying information**.

Our site may contain links to other sites that are not managed or maintained by the SETI Institute. The inclusion of a link to another site from seti.org does not imply any endorsement of that site's privacy policies, practices or content. Your dealings with these sites are covered only by the privacy policies listed on those sites. 

We have created this statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. We do not collect personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. Providing such information is strictly voluntary. This policy is your guide to how we will handle information we learn about you from your visit to our Web site.

 **Reading or Downloading**  

We collect and store only the following information about you: the name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, aol.com, if you are connecting from an America Online account, or princeton.edu if you are connecting from Princeton University's domain), the date and time you access our site, and the Internet address of the Web site from which you linked to our site. We use the information we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, and to help us make our site more useful to visitors.

 **Online Profile Updates and Donations**  

If you complete the Profile update form and share your personally identifying information, this information will be used only to provide you with more targeted content. We may use your contact information to send further information about our organization or to contact you when necessary. You may always opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the "Opt Out" section below. 

**Sending us an email**

You also may decide to send us personally identifying information, for example, in an electronic mail message containing a question or comment, or by filling out a Web form that provides us this information. We use personally identifying information from email primarily to respond to your requests. We may forward your email to other employees who are better able to answer you questions. We may also use your email to contact you in the future about our programs that may be of interest. 

We want to be very clear: We will not obtain personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. Providing such information is strictly voluntary. Except as might be required by law, we do not share any information we receive with any outside parties. 

If you sign up for one of our email lists, we will only send you the kinds of information you have requested. We won't share your name or email address with any outside parties.  

Opt-Out or Change Your Contact Information: Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us by emailing [jchynoweth@seti.org](mailto:jchynoweth@seti.org).  You may choose to receive only specific communications or none at all. You may also update your contact information previously provided to us. You can not remove yourself from our database, but you can prevent unwanted communication. 

**Credit card information**

The SETI Insitute uses secure server software (SSL) that is the industry standard and is among the best software available today for secure commerce transactions. It encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card number, name and address, so that it cannot be read as the information travels over the Internet.

Under the Fair Credit Billing Act, your bank cannot hold you liable for more than $50.00 of fraudulent charges. In the event of an unauthorized charge to your credit card you must: 

1\. Write to the creditor at the address given for "billing inquiries," not the address for sending your payments, and include your name, address, account number and a description of the billing error.

2\. Send your letter so that it reaches the creditor within 60 days after the first bill containing the error was mailed to you.

 **Use of Text and Images**  

If you would like to publish information that you find on our Web site, please send your request to info@seti.org. Where text or images are posted on our site with the permission of the original copyright holder, a copyright statement appears at the bottom of the page. 

**Have a question that was not answered here? Contact us at[info@seti.org](mailto:info@seti.org)**
